and today we are going to make
a trading bot using python the reason
why
is because everybody around me seems to
be doing trading
now the strategy to make money with this
bot is very very simple but it's very
smart
check it out we are going to buy bitcoin
when it's cheap
and we're going to sell bitcoin when
it's expensive i know
amazing strategy now
to try to guess if bitcoin is cheap and
it might become expensive
later we're going to use something
called an indicator
an indicator for example is when you are
on the park and you see that there's
clouds coming in
dark clouds coming that might be an
indicator that is going to rain
soon it's the same thing with the market
with the stock market with trading
we're going to use the most simple
indicator and we're going to hope
that hopefully we can make at least one
cent
or at least one dollar of profit with
this indicator all right so i already
have
the code that makes a graph so i can
show you the indicator
this graph shows you the price of
bitcoin
per hour for the last 1000 hours plus
the simple moving average simple moving
average is the name of the indicator
we're going to use and it's basically
the average price so in this case as you
can see right here
it went up and then right here it went
down so the price is
always dancing with the simple moving
average if the price
crosses the simple moving average going
up that might mean that the market is
going on an
upward direction if the price crosses
moving average
down that might mean that the market is
going on a downward direction and in
these sorts of
stroke as you can see here here it
crossed up
and it sort of went up and then when it
crossed down it kept going down
so this can show us a little bit of a
trend that could form the strategy is
gonna be
that when we see this happening like
this for example right here
when we see this happening we are going
to buy
so let me show you with arrows and stuff
when we would buy and when we would be
selling
okay and this is how it looks like this
is when i put the arrows of buying and
selling
here we would have bought and then we
could have sold that just a little bit
of money that would mean like
two cents of money but it would be good
again here buying and selling as you can
see the price crossed
we kept going up and then the moment we
saw red boom
we sold so this thing actually might
work
we might make one dollar at least
hopefully i will make one dollar from
this
okay here we lost money so
now that we know and we visualized how
it would work i am going to add some
nice
print statements and do the calculation
of how much money we would have made
okay because again always test this
thing with historical
data all right i think i have good news
using the last 1 000 hours okay
if we were playing with 1
000 so for example here as you can see
we would have bought at 19 a 596 and we
sold at seven that was a ten dollar
profit
boom okay next one that was an 18 profit
awesome then we lost ten dollars already
hey
look oh my god there was a trade we
bought at four
one six we sold at six thirty one
sweet at the end we did so many trades
they oh look at this
we made 33 dollars we run
this bot from august 30
of 2020 until october 8th that is today
we would have made 33 dollars
i know what you might be thinking that
if we run the boat from
august 30 to almost october just making
33 dollars it's a really
return you are right it is a very
bad return but still
that is money that in theory we didn't
have and in theory we made
like i said this is historical data so
we need to test this for real
i already have the logic of finding the
simple moving average i already have the
logic of when to buy when to sell now i
just need to connect with the binance
api
shouldn't take long and we can finally
test this bot so i'm gonna put a
thousand dollars on my binance account
and we're gonna be playing around with
one thousand dollars the thing is though
that we don't have the time
to test the bot for such a long period
of time
well i'm gonna test this by the minute
okay so we'll see
how that's different but we need testing
we need it today and i want to see if i
can make some money
sorry not money cents i want to make
sense if i make
sense i'll be happy so like i said i
already have 500 dollars
in so now what i have to do is buy
500 more of usdt
and you will see look 500 that is
roughly 495
usdt and here we go
let's buy okay
confirm the order okay let's go
all right look at this purchase
completed
i just spent five hundred dollars for a
video that's my wallet right
there
uh look this is very important we have
nine
nine sixty five so it's almost almost a
thousand dollars a little bit less
so it's true we have this so now
let's get started
[Music]
so i'm done with the code i just removed
all the chart code and i just added the
binance code okay
now binance has a sweet api so we just
connect to it but basically we're going
to
buy and we're going to sell when some
conditions happen let's start this thing
and see the state of our money let's go
i believe in my code i believe on
everything that i said
let's test this and see how much sense
we make
[Music]
all right so i killed the bot i want to
show you
on my dashboard on binance what happened
okay so we bought at 96
and we sold at 91 so we lost money there
we bought 69 sell that 70 buy 71
sell 69 lost money buy 68
sell 68 lost money buy 69
sell 70 good buy 70
sell 71. so it looks like we made some
money but
actually we lost money overall
even when we bought in a cheap price and
we sold on an expensive price
we lost money the reason why we lost
money is actually because
of the commissions and the fees of the
exchange
for example here i bought at 570 and i
sold at 571
that means i should have made money but
actually because
of the exchange as you can see here i
actually lost
eight cents so that sucks now
how to fix this the historical data that
i showed you that made like 30
as a profit that was for every 30 minute
period not one minute period
30 minutes the problem with minutes is
that they are so small
that it never changes it's like this
look the price is like this
we need something like this to make the
money and this doesn't happen
all the time every day we need to wait
for a longer time so maybe if i run this
thing
for at least a month we'll see
if it works also with 30 minute periods
instead of one minute periods
now another thing is that i believe
every time i send an order to the
exchange the price
changes so quickly that my order arrives
to the exchange and maybe
while it takes time to fulfill then the
price changes so that's another problem
and maybe instead of using python and
the rest api i use
something like go and web sockets so
even faster
we'll see but so far we didn't make any
money now i'm happy
because the strategy works and we could
test it and that's the whole point we
tested it
and i feel good we bought at cheap price
and we sold
at an expensive price it's amazing to be
a programmer in my opinion it's because
of this that i love being a programmer
that's it for this video let me know in
the comments if you feel like you want
to see
more of this content should i work more
on this bot until i can buy myself a
nice apathy
or should i invest my money somewhere
else
i don't know we'll see let me know in
the comments maybe this is the beginning
of a
series of optimizing the bot and
whatever
thank you so much for watching thank you
for your support don't forget to be
happy today take care of yourself
eat kimchi
you